Hoang Dinh Quang

Thach That, Hanoi, Vietnam (+84) 1646097953 quanghdse03459@fpt.edu.vn miumiu@azurewebsites.net (blog)

Summary: Last-year software engineering student with 1 years experience coding technically web applications using Node.js, Mongo.Db, Elastic Search and more. Proficient in Javascript, HTML, CSS and C++ language. Interested in solving algorithmic problems for ACM/ICPC Programming Contest in online judges.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Languages	Operator	Platform, Framework	Database	Other Skills
- C/ C++	- Linux	- Node.js	- MongoDb	- Email Marketing
- Javascript	- Windows	- Elastic Search	- SQL	
- HTML, CSS			- Redis	
- Python				

EDUCATION	
FPT University – Bachelor of Software Engineering Phan Boi Chau High School for Gifted Student – Informatics	2013-2018 2010-2013
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	

Saolasoft, Inc 9/2016 – present

A technology start-up based in Denver, U.S.

Remote Research Assistant

Responsibilities:

- Research public health trend based on data from social network (Facebook, Twitter)
- Crawl data and develop data mining techniques using Python

Line-Century Global .JSC

4/2016 - 8/2016

A fast-growing technology start-up base in Hanoi, Vietnam.

Full-stack developer Internship

Worked closely with other developers to develop and launch features related to education and finance of web and mobile applications.

Responsibilities:

- Maintain back-end system for education mobile games using Node.js, Parse Cloud and MongoDB
- Develop notification system for a financial application using Node.js, PostgreSQL and some thirdparty tools like Onesignal and Mailgun
- Develop a payment system for company using Node.js and Stripe
- Develop company's website using Express.js and MongoDB
- Implementing digital marketing programs (email and social network marketing campaigns)
- Track, analyze website analytics and optimize search engine recommendations

FPT Software 4/2015 – 7/2015

The leading Southeast Asia IT outsourcing provider

Software engineer Internship

Responsibilities:

- Implement some basic feature of industrial printer interface project.
- Implement automated unit test software.
- Attend GIT version control system training program.

AWARD

•	Golden Toad Award - The most outstanding student of FPT University	2016
•	Social Activity Contributor of FPT University	2015
•	2 nd prize ACM-ICPC Asia Regional Round Programming Contest	2015
•	1st prize ACM-ICPC Vietnam National Round Programming Contest	2015
•	1st prize of FPT University Informatics Olympiad	2015
•	Honorable mention prize - Asia Regional Round Programming Contest	2014
•	2 nd prize – ACM-ICPC Vietnam National Final Round Programming Contest	2014
•	1st prize – ACM-ICPC Vietnam National First Round Programming Contest	2014
•	Champion prize - FPT University Informatics Olympiad	2014
•	3 rd prize – Coding Inspiration – FPT University Software Development Contest	2014
•	2 nd runner up - Fsoft Code-camp – FPT Software Algorithm Contest	2014
•	3 rd prize – Vietnam Olympiad in Informatics	2013
•	3 rd prize – Vietnam Olympiad in Informatics	2012

•	Fuyo Scholarship	 Fuyo Corporation 	2016
•	Panasonic Scholarship	 Panasonic Vietnam Co,Ltd 	2016
•	The Story of Peace Scholarship for gifted student	- Tuoitre Newspaper	2016
•	Dam Phu My Scholarship for gifted student	- Petro Vietnam Corporation	2015
•	Nguyen Van Dao Scholarship for gifted student	- FPT University	2013
•	Odon Vallet Scholarship for gifted student	- Meeting Vietnam Organization	2013

PROJECTS

Saolasoft Payment Tool

08/2016

Project Description:

A system help customer to transfer money to company's bank account using credit card and track the payment reports.

Team size: 1

Project size: 1 months

Responsibilities: Full-stack developer. I am responsible for developing both front-end and back-end for

this website.

Technologies Used: Node.js, MongoDb, Stripe

FUL66 Website 08/2016

Project Description:

A website that represent company's product: http://ful66.net

Team size: 1

Project size: 1 months

Responsibilities: Fullstack Developer, SEO. I am responsible for developing both front-end, back-end and

SEO for this website.

Technologies Used: Node.js, Express, MongoDb

Vua kien thuc game online

05/2016

Project Description:

This is product of the start-up that I intern. A game online where users challenge their friends by answering trivia questions in 6 categories.

https://itunes.apple.com/vn/app/vua-kien-thuc/id1077184133?mt=8

Team size: 4

Project size: 3 months

Responsibilities: Backend developer.

Technologies Used: Node.js, MongoDb, Redis, Parse, OneSignal

Stock-mobi alert system

04/2016

Project Description:

A server that notify to user whenever a certain stock price exceeds or are below a threshold through email, mobile notification and SMS.

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/stockmobi-stockcharts-screener/id1059686569

Team size: 2

Project size: 3 weeks
Responsibilities: Backend developer
Technologies Used: Node.js, OneSignal, Mailgun, PostgreSQL